Nadav Vilder

(510) 379-8530 · Berkeley, CA · nadavilder@gmail.com github.com/nadavilder · linkedin.com/in/nadavilder Authorized To Work (Green Card)

Dedicated Software Engineer with 3+ years of developing web applications using the most modern languages and frameworks. Led Siemens Application Lifecycle Management app, supporting Agile methodologies and collaboration. Enthusiastic about making a difference and contributing to growth in a dynamic role. Open to remote/hybrid/office-only roles.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages: JavaScript, Python, C#, Java
- Web Frameworks: Next.js, React.js, Node.js, jQuery, HTML, CSS
- Databases: AWS (S3), SQL, PostgreSQL, Lucene
- Agile Methodologies

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer, Siemens Digital Industries Software

Aug 2021 - Sep 2023

- **Application Development Leadership:** Spearheaded the development of Siemens ALM internal application enhancing the experience for 2,000+ employees, resulted accelerated deployments, richer analytics, and superior project outcomes
- Agile Method Expertise: Demonstrated expertise in Agile methodologies by leading the development of 100+ features. Utilized
 CI/CD and Gitlab to enhance application functionality, fostering collaborations across development teams and ensuring a
 seamless workflow
- **Strategic Collaboration Facilitation:** Led the Siemens Startups forum, facilitating collaboration and innovative idea exchange. This initiative contributed to the acceleration of integrity and innovation within the organization
- **Effective Team Coordination:** Ensured effective coordination among PMs, UX/UI specialists, and stakeholders, aligning all project aspects professionally and efficiently

Software Engineer, milab - Media Innovation Lab

Jan 2021 - Jul 2021

• Efficient Sensors Programming: Utilized advanced C++ techniques to optimize sensors and Arduino programming, improving real-time feedback in the prototype for a better user experience

Master Sergeant, Israel Navy Submarines

Oct 2013 - Jun 2018

- **Team Leadership:** Commanded a skilled team of 12 soldiers through high-pressure scenarios in specialized missions, showcasing strong leadership under demanding conditions
- **Problem Solving:** Oversaw computers and sensors, installing and ensuring seamless operations and resolving technical issues for optimized system performance

CERTIFICATIONS

Google for Startups Academy

Oct 2022 – Feb 2023

• Designed an app for women in domestic violent relationships, so that they could move to a safer place for a couple of days and take care of themselves emotionally and strategically, achieving 3rd place among 2,000+ applications

Complete Web Development Bootcamp – Udemy: Became a Full-Stack Web Developer

Python - The Practical Guide - Udemy: Built my own Blockchain and Cryptocurrency

SAFe for Teams Course (5.1) – SCALED AGILE: Learned the skills to be a high-performing member of an Agile Release Train

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science (BS) in Computer Science, Reichman University, Herzliya, Israel

Oct 2019 - Nov 2022

- Completed a hands-on web app development course, building an end-to-end E-commerce web app with Node.js and React.js
- Certification studies in data science with Scikit-Learn, NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn
- Dev club: IMDb Web app, Kaggle competitions

SOFT SKILLS

Communication, Creative Problem-Solving, Fast-Learner, Team Collaboration, Empathy, Time Management, Ambitious

LANGUAGES

English - Fluent, Hebrew - Native, Spanish - Basic